In this video we're going to talk about ambiguous context free grammars in
在本视频中，我们将讨论以下内容中的模糊上下文无关文法
programming languages and what to do about them. We'll begin by looking at our
编程语言以及如何处理它们。我们先来看看我们的
favorite grammar for expressions over + and and identifiers and we'll just look
+和和标识符上的表达式最喜欢的语法，我们只看一下
at the string id id + id. Now it turns out that this particular string and let's
在字符串id+id处。现在发现这个特殊的字符串，让我们
write it down one more time, id id + id. This string has two parse tree using this
再写一遍，id，id+id。此字符串有两个使用此字符串的分析树
grammar. Let's do the Parse tree on the left first. We begin with the start symbol
语法。让我们先做左边的解析树。我们从开始符号开始
e and the first production in this derivation that gives us this Parse tree
E和这个派生中的第一个结果，它给出了这个解析树
must be that e goes to e + e. E + e And then we replace the left most e by e e.
一定是e变成了e+e，然后我们把最左边的e换成了e。
We use the production e goes to e e and we still have the plus e left over and at
我们用e到e的乘积，我们还有剩余的加e和
this point you can see that we're going to get this parse tree. We've done with those
在这一点上，您可以看到我们将获得这个解析树。我们已经处理完了那些
two productions. We have done this much. The construction of the parse tree and the
两部作品。我们已经做了这么多。解析树的构造和
rest of productions are just generating these id's. So that's a three more
睡觉的制作就是在生成这些id。所以这又是3
productions and we can see that, you know if we do those we'll get id id + id no
我们可以看到，如果我们这样做，我们会得到id+id no
problem, alright. So now let's switch and do the derivation on the right or excuse
有问题，好吧。现在让我们交换一下，做右边或借口上的推导
me, the parse tree on the right so this begins also with e. But this time we use
Me，右侧的解析树也以e开头，但这一次我们使用
the production e goes to e e first, all right? And now we're gonna replace the
作品e先去e e，好吗？现在我们要替换
right most e. By e goes to e + e so we have e e + e and now we've, with those
右边大部分e，by e是e+e，所以我们有e，e+e，现在我们用这些
two productions we've done this portion of the parse tree and once again with three
我们已经完成了解析树的这一部分的两个结果，并再次使用了三个
more productions we can get to id id + id so there you can see we've got two
更多的作品，我们可以找到id，id+id，所以你可以看到我们有两个
derivations. That produced two distinct Parse trees. And just to be completely
派生。这就产生了两个截然不同的解析树。我想说的是，我想说的是
clear about this, in this case we're getting two different Parse trees. Each of
明确这一点，在本例中，我们得到两个不同的解析树。每一个
these derivation, each of these Parse trees has many derivations. Each Parse
这些派生，这些解析树中的每一个都有很多派生。每次解析
tree has a left most derivation, a right most derivation and many other
树有最左边的派生、最右边的派生和许多其他派生
derivations. This situation is something different. Here we have two derivations
派生。这种情况是不同的。这里我们有两个派生
that yield completely different Parse trees and that is the sign or the
生成完全不同的解析树，这就是符号或
definition of an ambiguous grammar. So a grammar is ambiguous if it has more than
歧义语法的定义。因此，如果一个语法包含的内容多于一个，则该语法是不明确的
one Parse tree for some string. And another way of saying the same thing is
某个字符串的一棵解析树。另一种说法是同样的事情
that there is more than one right most or left most derivation for some string. So
某个字符串有多个最右边或最左边的派生。所以
if some string has two right most derivations or more or two left
如果某个字符串有两个最右侧派生词或更多或两个左侧派生词
derivations or more then the, that string will have two distinct parse trees and
派生或更多派生，该字符串将有两个截然不同的分析树，并且
that grammar will be ambiguous. Ambiguity is bad. If you have multiple parse trees
那个语法将是模棱两可的。模棱两可是不好的。如果您有多个解析树
for some program then that essentially means that you're leaving it up to the
对于某些程序而言，这实质上意味着您将把它留给
compiler to pick which of those two possible interpretations of the program
编译器选择这两种可能的程序解释中的哪一种
you want it to generate code for and that's not a good idea. We don't like to
您希望它为生成代码，这不是一个好主意。我们不喜欢
have ambiguity in our programming languages and leave decisions about what
在我们的编程语言中有模棱两可的地方，让我们来决定什么是
the program means up to the compiler.
该程序的意思是最高可达编译器。